

CONTACT INFORMATION

PHONE

+94 76 555 9364

EMAIL

kithminiranathunga13@gmail.com

ADDRESS

Gampaha, Sri Lanka

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kithminiranathunga-36a81520a/

PORTFOLIO

https://kithmini13.github.io/Portfolio/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Python
- R
- SQL
- C
- C++

Tools and Platforms

- GIT
- GitHub
- Postman

Data Visualization & Analytics

- Power BI
- Tableau
- MS Excel
- Machine Learning
- ETL Development

Version controlling

- GitHub
- Bitbucket

Cloud platforms

- AWS
- Azure

Database Handling

- SQL (Oracle, MySQL, MS SQL)
- PostgreSQL

Web Development

- HTML
- JS
- CSS

KITHMINI RANATHUNGA

Data Science

I am an ambitious individual with a great passion for the information technology industry. I have recently graduate at Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT), following BSc in Information Technology specialization in Data Science, having a passion in Data science, Artificial Intelligence and developing innovative programs that expedite the effectiveness of organizational success. I am aiming to utilize my strong skills and analytical ability to achieve each goal.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Business Intelligence Engineer Dtech (Pvt) Ltd (June 2024 – Present)

- Developed and maintained DSI Finance Dashboard, DSI Manufacturing Dashboard, DSI Material Analysis Dashboard and their reports using SQL and Power BI, enabling real-time data access for stakeholders.
- Analyzed large datasets to identify trends, patterns, and insights.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to understand data requirements and deliver timely, accurate reports.

Trainee Associate Data Engineer Epic Lanka (Pvt) Ltd (Dec 2023- June 2024)

- Dashboard creation using Tableau for bank recovery team.
- Implement an end-to-end Azure ETL project, enabling smooth data migration from on-premises sources to Azure Data Factory. Leveraged Azure Storage and Data bricks for data transformation, ultimately setting up a data warehouse on Azure Synapse. Integrated Power BI to provide dynamic data visualization and reporting features.

Intern Artificial Intelligence Epic Lanka (Pvt) Ltd (Feb 2023- Dec 2023)

 The development of an EKYC (Electronically Know Your Customer) project for Seylan Bank.

Document details extraction using OCR using python - Flask Real time liveness checks using java scripts using python - Django Face image Matching with open cv using python - Flask

- Developed the ICAO photo Studio Solution to automatically validate passports against ICAO standards using python.
- Researched and developed a ML model for predictive analytics in banking.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. (Hons) in Information and Technology Specializing in Data Science-2024Sri Lanka Institute of Information and Technology (SLIIT)

Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Physical Science (Reading)

University of Kelaniya

G.C.E Advanced Level Examination

Rathnavali Balika Vidyalaya, Gampaha – 2019(Physical Science Stream)

- Java Scripts
- React JS

Designing Tools

- Drow.io
- Figma

SOFT SKILLS

- Analytical and problem-Solving Skills
- Data Storytelling
- Research and development
- Report writing and presenting
- Problem Solving
- Decision making
- Good communication
- Self-motivated
- Curiosity and passion for learning

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Active Member of Leo Club at SLIIT
- Active Member of Data Science Student's Community at SLLIT
- Active Member of Mathematic Society at University of Kelaniya

CERTIFICATIONS

- PL -300 Power BI Data analyst Associate Microsoft
- Certificate course in Microsoft Office.

University of Kelaniya – 2016

Certificate course in English.
 British council –Sri Lanka - 2019

INTERESTS

- Data Science
- Data Engineering
- Data Analysts
- Machine Learning
- Cloud Computing
- Business Intelligence Engineering
- Mathematics

RESEARCHES

Research - Save Ride Vehicle alert system for drivers (2023)

Driver's drowsiness and distraction detection using eye movements. Python modeling to get predictions. Mobile App development to provide Alerts

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Research project - Safe Driving System for Drivers

Developing a safe driving system for drivers detecting eye moments, mouth yawing, hand pose detection and head pose detection.

Using google Colab, VS code, Django.

• Bank loan Prediction System (ATR)

Fundamentals of Data Mining-Group project [2022] Implement a model with frontend Ability to Repay (ATR) Prediction (Machine Learning model) Application for bank loans.

Using Google Colab, Python, Visual Studio, Flask and Heroku.

• Museum Artworks Analytic System

Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence -individual Project [2022]

- 1.Data Warehousing, Develop ETL (Extract, Transform, Load)
- 2.Creation of SSRS Reports
- **3.OLAP Operations**
- 4. Dashnoard Creation using Power BI

Using SSMS, SSIS, SSDT, SSAS, Visual Studio, Report Service and Power BI

PUBLICATIONS

Behavior Analysis of Drivers Using Machine Learning, International Research Journal of Innovations in Engineering and Technology-IRJIET November 2023 https://irjiet.com/Volume-7/Issue-11-November-2023/Behavior-Analysis-ofDrivers-Using-Machine-Learning/1920

REFEREES

Mr. Lahiru Maharamba

Head of Business Intelligence Epic Lanka (Pvt) Ltd

Email: Lahiru_m@epiclanka.net Contact Number: 071 5728154

I hereby undersigned and certified that the particulars furnished by me are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Signature